<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mac on GUI Free Life</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/tags/mac/</link><description>Recent content in mac on GUI Free Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://guifreelife.com/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Testing Openshift Origin V3 with Ansible and Vagrant on OS X</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2015/06/28/Testing-Openshift-Origin-V3-with-Ansible-and-Vagrant-on-OS-X/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2015/06/28/Testing-Openshift-Origin-V3-with-Ansible-and-Vagrant-on-OS-X/</guid><description>The OpenShift Origin project provides Ansible playbooks and roles for installing OpenShift on various infratructure. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try out the example using Vagrant and VirtualBox on my Mac. I&amp;rsquo;m not very familiar with Vagrant or OpenShift v3 yet, so I&amp;rsquo;m just going to think out loud and see how it goes. I&amp;rsquo;ve also recently started testing OpenShift Enterprise.
Some Background OpenShift Origin is an opensource PaaS (platform as a service).</description></item><item><title>Zimbra Exchange Web Services Crashes OS X Mail.app</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2015/02/17/Zimbra-Exchange-Web-Services-Crashes-OS-X-Mail.app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2015/02/17/Zimbra-Exchange-Web-Services-Crashes-OS-X-Mail.app/</guid><description>Zimbra added EWS support in ZCS 8.5. Right around that time OS X 10.10 was released. Cool! Let&amp;rsquo;s start syncing all our things to our brand new Mail.app, Calendar.app, and Contacts.app over HTTPS!
Strangely, this page says that:
ZCS 8.5 targeted EWS support ONLY with Outlook for Mac&amp;rsquo;s. There was no testing or expectation that the native mac apps would work with the EWS configuration type.
Really?! I hope that&amp;rsquo;s not true.</description></item><item><title>Openshift V2 and Flask with Virtualenv on OS X</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2014/11/22/Openshift-and-Flask-with-Virtualenv-on-OS-X/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2014/11/22/Openshift-and-Flask-with-Virtualenv-on-OS-X/</guid><description>Create a flask app for Openshift with a matching local python virtualenv to perform local testing.
In this case we&amp;rsquo;ll use Python 2.7 on Mac OS X 10.9.
Overview of the steps Install Homebrew Install Python Development Environment on Mac OS X Install rhc client tools. Install and Configure a Python Flask for OpenShift Installing Homebrew Ready the system for Homebrew First unhide ~/Library folder.
Open Finder Press shift-command-H Press command-J Check Show Library Folder Now Setup shell environment Some of these settings are only relevant to later steps, but go ahead and put them all in now.</description></item></channel></rss>