<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RHACM on GUI Free Life</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/tags/RHACM/</link><description>Recent content in RHACM on GUI Free Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://guifreelife.com/tags/RHACM/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Placements to Apply Open Cluster Management Policies to Kubernetes Clusters</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2024/03/11/Placing-Open-Cluster-Management-Policies-on-Kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2024/03/11/Placing-Open-Cluster-Management-Policies-on-Kubernetes/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://access.redhat.com/products/red-hat-advanced-cluster-management-for-kubernetes/" title="RHACM">Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management&lt;/a> (RHACM) enables Open Cluster Management policy driven governance of an entire fleet of Kubernetes clusters. Associating policies with the appropriate clusters is a very flexible operation and requires understanding resources like Placements and ManagedClusterSetBindings. So let&amp;rsquo;s get familiar!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hybrid Cloud Management With Red Hat</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/09/19/Hybrid-Cloud-Management-with-Red-Hat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/09/19/Hybrid-Cloud-Management-with-Red-Hat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whether workloads are in the datacenter, in the cloud, or even in multiple clouds, OpenShift provides a consistent experience. And the Hybrid Cloud Console is your entry point for Red Hat cloud services to enable the most effective use of each environment. This video demo walks through the provisioning of &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/cloud-computing/openshift/aws" title="Red Hat OpenShift Service on AWS">ROSA&lt;/a> and using Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management with EKS. Finally, &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/management/advanced-cluster-management" title="Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes">RHACM&lt;/a> policies are deployed to ensure automatic application of Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management Walkthrough</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/12/21/Red-Hat-Advanced-Cluster-Management-Walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/12/21/Red-Hat-Advanced-Cluster-Management-Walkthrough/</guid><description>&lt;p>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes, &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/management/advanced-cluster-management" title="Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes">RHACM&lt;/a>, built on the Open Cluster Management &lt;a href="https://open-cluster-management.io/" title="Open Cluster Management">project&lt;/a>, manages Kubernetes distributions like AKS, EKS, GKE, and OpenShift including the workloads they host. Read on for a demonstration of RHACM features like Cluster Hibernation, Cluster Pools, Multi-cluster application deployment and Observability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skip to the end for the complete &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rS9IatJBRP8" title="YouTube Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management Demos">video demo&lt;/a> or take your time and stroll through a few quick GUI Free reanimations on your way there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recovering kubeconfig for a Cluster Created with RHACM</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/08/13/RHACM-Recover-Created-Cluster-Credentials-and-Kubeconfig/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/08/13/RHACM-Recover-Created-Cluster-Credentials-and-Kubeconfig/</guid><description>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes and it&amp;rsquo;s upstream Open Cluster Management automate cluster lifecycle management from creation, configuration, upgrade, and destruction.
If a cluster is created by RHACM you may need to download the kubeadmin password and the kubeconfig. This is easily accomplished by browsing to the RHACM cluster overview, but how do you do the same from the CLI?
ClusterDeployment The creation of a cluster starts with a ClusterDeployment which will be interpreted by Hive.</description></item></channel></rss>