<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hybrid-cloud on GUI Free Life</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/tags/hybrid-cloud/</link><description>Recent content in hybrid-cloud on GUI Free Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://guifreelife.com/tags/hybrid-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hybrid Cloud Management With Red Hat</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/09/19/Hybrid-Cloud-Management-with-Red-Hat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/09/19/Hybrid-Cloud-Management-with-Red-Hat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whether workloads are in the datacenter, in the cloud, or even in multiple clouds, OpenShift provides a consistent experience. And the Hybrid Cloud Console is your entry point for Red Hat cloud services to enable the most effective use of each environment. This video demo walks through the provisioning of &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/cloud-computing/openshift/aws" title="Red Hat OpenShift Service on AWS">ROSA&lt;/a> and using Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management with EKS. Finally, &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/management/advanced-cluster-management" title="Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes">RHACM&lt;/a> policies are deployed to ensure automatic application of Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recovering kubeconfig for a Cluster Created with RHACM</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/08/13/RHACM-Recover-Created-Cluster-Credentials-and-Kubeconfig/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/08/13/RHACM-Recover-Created-Cluster-Credentials-and-Kubeconfig/</guid><description>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes and it&amp;rsquo;s upstream Open Cluster Management automate cluster lifecycle management from creation, configuration, upgrade, and destruction.
If a cluster is created by RHACM you may need to download the kubeadmin password and the kubeconfig. This is easily accomplished by browsing to the RHACM cluster overview, but how do you do the same from the CLI?
ClusterDeployment The creation of a cluster starts with a ClusterDeployment which will be interpreted by Hive.</description></item></channel></rss>