<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OCP4 on GUI Free Life</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/tags/OCP4/</link><description>Recent content in OCP4 on GUI Free Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://guifreelife.com/tags/OCP4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Storing OpenShift Credentials with 1Password</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2023/09/22/Storing-OpenShift-Credentials-with-1Password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2023/09/22/Storing-OpenShift-Credentials-with-1Password/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you find yourself frequently rebuilding OpenShift clusters and potentially reusing cluster names, you may find it challanging to manage the credentials consistently and securely. Here is a solution using &lt;a href="https://developer.1password.com/docs/cli/get-started/" title="Get started with 1Password CLI">1Password&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accessing the Ceph CLI with OpenShift Data Foundation</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2023/04/06/Accessing-Ceph-CLI-with-OpenShift-Data-Foundation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2023/04/06/Accessing-Ceph-CLI-with-OpenShift-Data-Foundation/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Ceph Toolbox is not recommended or supported for use with OpenShift Data Foundation, but sometimes you want a client to troubleshoot with anyway.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Extracting TLS CA Certificates from Kubeconfig File</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2023/03/09/Extracting-CA-Certs-From-Kubeconfig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2023/03/09/Extracting-CA-Certs-From-Kubeconfig/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenShift creates a number of Certificate Authorities to sign TLS certificates which secure functions including load balancing of the API and Ingress services.
Recent versions of openshift-install will place all the CA certificates in the generated &lt;code>auth/kubeconfig&lt;/code> file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is how to extract and split those certificates into individual files which eases the process of trusting them particularly on a Mac.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autoscaling OpenShift Workloads With Custom Prometheus Metrics</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/11/03/Autoscaling-OpenShift-Workloads-with-Custom-Prometheus-Metrics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/11/03/Autoscaling-OpenShift-Workloads-with-Custom-Prometheus-Metrics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes enables the automated scaling of applications to meet workload demands. Historically only memory and CPU consumption could be considered in scaling decisions, but the OpenShift Custom Metrics Autoscaler operator and KEDA remove that limitation. Read on to learn how OpenShift enables auto scaling based on the metrics that are important to your business.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenShift Virtualization on vSphere</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/05/13/OpenShift-Virtualization-on-vSphere/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/05/13/OpenShift-Virtualization-on-vSphere/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenShift Virtualization builds upon &lt;a href="https://kubevirt.io" title="KubeVirt.io">KubeVirt&lt;/a> to provide a container native home for your virtual machine workloads. While bare metal is the only officially support platform today, this post will walk through enabling OpenShift Virtualization on vSphere in a lab environment. With nested virtualization you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to spin up containerized VMs bridged to your physical networks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Debugging AWS STS Authentication for OpenShift Operators</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/03/10/Debugging-AWS-STS-Authentication-for-OpenShift-Operators/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/03/10/Debugging-AWS-STS-Authentication-for-OpenShift-Operators/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenShift supports granular AWS permissions for pods running cluster operators or even user applications. This enhances security by providing only the necessary privileges and nothing more. This post explores debugging authN and authZ of pods attempting to use fine grained IAM roles in combination with AWS secure token service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Cross-platform Windows and Linux Application to OpenShift</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/07/10/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/07/10/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>An application can sometimes require diverse components that span technology stacks. There may be a depency on a legacy component built for Windows which may not be suitable for deployment to Linux. The good news is it may still be suitable for deployment to Kubernetes. With a Windows node in your OpenShift cluster you can deploy cross-platform applications that can simultaneously leverage the strengths of Linux and Windows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding a Windows Node to an OpenShift Cluster</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/06/03/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/06/03/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Windows Machine Config Operator builds and configures Windows machines to act as nodes in an OpenShift cluster enabling cross platform workloads. This post will demonstrate the addition of a Windows node to an existing cluster and explore the integration of Windows and Kubernetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installing OpenShift on Azure for Windows Containers</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/05/18/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/05/18/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Adding support for Windows nodes in your OpenShift cluster is a day 2 operation that requires preparation at install time.
It is important to accommodate the hybrid networking requirements for Windows Kubernetes nodes.
Azure specific tasks and gotchas are highlighted in this part 1 of 3 while laying the groundwork applicable to deploying OpenShift on any provider in preparation for managing Windows containers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How do OpenShift Over The Air Updates Work?</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/03/09/Understanding-OpenShift-Over-The-Air-Updates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/03/09/Understanding-OpenShift-Over-The-Air-Updates/</guid><description>OpenShift 4 extends the operator pattern introduced by CoreOS, and enables automated management of the Kubernetes cluster and the underlying resources including machine instances and operating system configuration. Operator driven over the air updates enable automated updates much like you are accustomed to receiving for your smart phone. What follows is a a technical exploration of the OpenShift over the air updates implementation.
Operators All the Way Down What is an &amp;ldquo;Operator&amp;rdquo;?</description></item><item><title>OpenShift 4 on OpenStack Networking and Installation</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2020/02/15/OpenShift-4-on-OpenStack-Networking-and-Installation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2020/02/15/OpenShift-4-on-OpenStack-Networking-and-Installation/</guid><description>OpenShift Containter Platform 4 is much more like Tectonic than OpenShift 3. Particularly when it comes to installation and node management. Rather then building machines and running an Ansible playbook to configure them you now have the option of setting a fewer paramters in an install config running an installer to build and configure the cluster from scratch.
I would like to illustrate how the basics of the networking might look when installing OpenShift on OpenStack.</description></item></channel></rss>