<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows on GUI Free Life</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in windows on GUI Free Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://guifreelife.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying a Cross-platform Windows and Linux Application to OpenShift</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/07/10/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/07/10/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>An application can sometimes require diverse components that span technology stacks. There may be a depency on a legacy component built for Windows which may not be suitable for deployment to Linux. The good news is it may still be suitable for deployment to Kubernetes. With a Windows node in your OpenShift cluster you can deploy cross-platform applications that can simultaneously leverage the strengths of Linux and Windows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding a Windows Node to an OpenShift Cluster</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/06/03/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/06/03/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Windows Machine Config Operator builds and configures Windows machines to act as nodes in an OpenShift cluster enabling cross platform workloads. This post will demonstrate the addition of a Windows node to an existing cluster and explore the integration of Windows and Kubernetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installing OpenShift on Azure for Windows Containers</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/05/18/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/05/18/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Adding support for Windows nodes in your OpenShift cluster is a day 2 operation that requires preparation at install time.
It is important to accommodate the hybrid networking requirements for Windows Kubernetes nodes.
Azure specific tasks and gotchas are highlighted in this part 1 of 3 while laying the groundwork applicable to deploying OpenShift on any provider in preparation for managing Windows containers.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>