<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>webinar on GUI Free Life</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/tags/webinar/</link><description>Recent content in webinar on GUI Free Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://guifreelife.com/tags/webinar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hybrid Cloud Management With Red Hat</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/09/19/Hybrid-Cloud-Management-with-Red-Hat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/09/19/Hybrid-Cloud-Management-with-Red-Hat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whether workloads are in the datacenter, in the cloud, or even in multiple clouds, OpenShift provides a consistent experience. And the Hybrid Cloud Console is your entry point for Red Hat cloud services to enable the most effective use of each environment. This video demo walks through the provisioning of &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/cloud-computing/openshift/aws" title="Red Hat OpenShift Service on AWS">ROSA&lt;/a> and using Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management with EKS. Finally, &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/management/advanced-cluster-management" title="Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes">RHACM&lt;/a> policies are deployed to ensure automatic application of Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security Walkthrough</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/12/22/Red-Hat-Advanced-Cluster-Security-Walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/12/22/Red-Hat-Advanced-Cluster-Security-Walkthrough/</guid><description>&lt;p>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security for Kubernetes enables organizations to securely build, deploy, and run cloud-native applications anywhere. This video demonstration walks through the major features of RHACS to demonstrate vulnerability management, network segmentation, custom security policies, and more!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management Walkthrough</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/12/21/Red-Hat-Advanced-Cluster-Management-Walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/12/21/Red-Hat-Advanced-Cluster-Management-Walkthrough/</guid><description>&lt;p>Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes, &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/technologies/management/advanced-cluster-management" title="Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes">RHACM&lt;/a>, built on the Open Cluster Management &lt;a href="https://open-cluster-management.io/" title="Open Cluster Management">project&lt;/a>, manages Kubernetes distributions like AKS, EKS, GKE, and OpenShift including the workloads they host. Read on for a demonstration of RHACM features like Cluster Hibernation, Cluster Pools, Multi-cluster application deployment and Observability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skip to the end for the complete &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rS9IatJBRP8" title="YouTube Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management Demos">video demo&lt;/a> or take your time and stroll through a few quick GUI Free reanimations on your way there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How do OpenShift Over The Air Updates Work?</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/03/09/Understanding-OpenShift-Over-The-Air-Updates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/03/09/Understanding-OpenShift-Over-The-Air-Updates/</guid><description>OpenShift 4 extends the operator pattern introduced by CoreOS, and enables automated management of the Kubernetes cluster and the underlying resources including machine instances and operating system configuration. Operator driven over the air updates enable automated updates much like you are accustomed to receiving for your smart phone. What follows is a a technical exploration of the OpenShift over the air updates implementation.
Operators All the Way Down What is an &amp;ldquo;Operator&amp;rdquo;?</description></item></channel></rss>