<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Operators on GUI Free Life</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/tags/operators/</link><description>Recent content in Operators on GUI Free Life</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://guifreelife.com/tags/operators/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenShift CoreOS On-Cluster Custom Node Image Layering</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2025/06/20/CoreOS-Image-Layering-Autofs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2025/06/20/CoreOS-Image-Layering-Autofs/</guid><description>&lt;p>CoreOS On-cluster Image Layering in OpenShift 4.19 allows modifications to node the operating system. This detailed walk through customizes the node operating system image by adding RPMs to support autofs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="http://guifreelife.com/coming-soon/" title="Configuring AutoFS on OpenShift">part 2&lt;/a> we will configure autofs and enable automatic filesystem mounting across cluster nodes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Managing Readable OpenShift MachineConfigs with Butane</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2025/05/29/Managing-OpenShift-Machine-Configuration-with-Butane-and-Ignition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2025/05/29/Managing-OpenShift-Machine-Configuration-with-Butane-and-Ignition/</guid><description>&lt;p>The OpenShift Machine Configuration Operator applies configuration changes to to nodes using a syntax called &lt;a href="https://coreos.github.io/ignition/specs/" title="CoreOS Ignition Spec">Ignition&lt;/a>,
but managing base64 encoded text can be challenging. What if I told you that you can use plain text and normal files?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Debugging AWS STS Authentication for OpenShift Operators</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/03/10/Debugging-AWS-STS-Authentication-for-OpenShift-Operators/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2022/03/10/Debugging-AWS-STS-Authentication-for-OpenShift-Operators/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenShift supports granular AWS permissions for pods running cluster operators or even user applications. This enhances security by providing only the necessary privileges and nothing more. This post explores debugging authN and authZ of pods attempting to use fine grained IAM roles in combination with AWS secure token service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Cross-platform Windows and Linux Application to OpenShift</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/07/10/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/07/10/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>An application can sometimes require diverse components that span technology stacks. There may be a depency on a legacy component built for Windows which may not be suitable for deployment to Linux. The good news is it may still be suitable for deployment to Kubernetes. With a Windows node in your OpenShift cluster you can deploy cross-platform applications that can simultaneously leverage the strengths of Linux and Windows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding a Windows Node to an OpenShift Cluster</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/06/03/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/06/03/OpenShift-Windows-Containers-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Windows Machine Config Operator builds and configures Windows machines to act as nodes in an OpenShift cluster enabling cross platform workloads. This post will demonstrate the addition of a Windows node to an existing cluster and explore the integration of Windows and Kubernetes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How do OpenShift Over The Air Updates Work?</title><link>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/03/09/Understanding-OpenShift-Over-The-Air-Updates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://guifreelife.com/blog/2021/03/09/Understanding-OpenShift-Over-The-Air-Updates/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenShift 4 extends the &lt;a href="https://coreos.com/blog/introducing-operator-framework" title="Introducing Operator Framework">operator pattern introduced by CoreOS&lt;/a>, and enables automated management of the Kubernetes cluster and the underlying resources including machine instances and operating system configuration. Operator driven over the air updates enable automated updates much like you are accustomed to receiving for your smart phone. What follows is a a technical exploration of the OpenShift over the air updates implementation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="operators-all-the-way-down">Operators All the Way Down&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://nara.getarchive.net/media/the-face-of-a-computer-operator-from-the-2134th-communications-squadron-is-2ca9c9">&lt;img src="http://guifreelife.com/images/the-face-of-a-computer-operator-from-the-2134th-communications-squadron-is-2ca9c9.jpg" alt="Computer Operator">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>